I-DA CHIANG

idchiang@ucsd.edu | (858) 999-1807 | LinkedIn: idchiang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Dust life cycle and the interstellar medium

I am interested in the evolution of dust grains in the interstellar medium. One of my project is measuring the spatially resolved dust-to-metals ratio in the nearby galaxies, and interpreting the results with dust chemical evolution models, simulations and auxiliary data.

HI 21 cm line and radio data reduction

The distribution of neutral gas is a key element in dust-to-metals ratio studies. The HI 21 cm line traces neutral hydrogen atoms in the ISM. I reduced new HI 21cm line data of ~ 30 galaxies observed by VLA with CASA. These new data allows us to construct a new dust-to-metals ratio survey in the nearby galaxies.

EXPERIENCE

University of California - San Diego, La Jolla, CA

Sep. 2014 - Est. Jun. 2021

Graduate Research Assistant

- Built a python-based toolkit for dust SED fitting and multi-wavelength data analysis.
- Analyzed the dust-to-gas and dust-to-metal ratios in the spiral galaxy M101.
- Analyzed the dust-to-metal ratio and CO-to-H₂ conversion factor in detail in 5 nearby galaxies.
- Examined the empirical radiation distribution law and the turbulent power spectrum in the local group galaxies with the dust SED fitting tools.
- Reduced H_I 21cm line data of ~30 galaxies observed by VLA with the Common Astronomy Software Applications package (CASA).

University of California - San Diego, La Jolla, CA

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2016

Teaching Assistant (TA) and Lab TA Coordinator

- Familiarized new teaching assistants with lab setups and teaching skills.
- Led discussion sessions, which helped ~ 40 students each week.
- Led introductory level physics lab, with 24 students per session.
- Improved course materials from feedback from teaching assistants and students.

National Taiwan University, Taipei City, Taiwan

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2014

Graduate Research Assistant

- Improved the photo-degradation reactor for wastewater treatment with plasmonic nano-particles.
- Built the protocol for maintaining/using the sputter machine and clean room.

Taiwan (R.O.C.) Armed Forces, Hsinchu County, Taiwan

Aug. 2011 - Jul. 2012

Second Lieutenant (Company second-in-command)

EDUCATION

University of California - San Diego

Ph.D. (Physics and Astronomy)

Adviser: Prof. Karin M. Sandstrom

National Taiwan University

Aug. 2012 - Jul. 2014

Sep. 2014 - Est. Jun. 2021

M.S. (Physics)

Thesis: "Plasmonic Enhanced Optical Disk Reactor for Wastewater Treatment"

Adviser: Prof. Din Ping Tsai

National Taiwan University B.S. (Physics)

Sep. 2007 - Jun. 2011

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS AS FIRST OR SECOND AUTHOR

- 4) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, E. Koch, K. Kreckel, A.K. Leroy, A. Schruba, D. Utomo, T. Williams, "Resolving the Dust-to-Metals Ratio and CO-to-H₂ Conversion Factor in the Nearby Universe", 2020, arXiv:2011.10561, accepted by ApJ.
- 3) E.W. Koch, **I-D. Chiang**, D. Utomo, J. Chastenet, A.K. Leroy, E.W. Rosolowsky, K.M. Sandstrom, "Spatial power spectra of dust across the Local Group: No constraint on disc scale height", 2020, MNRAS, 492, 2663.
- 2) D. Utomo, I-D. Chiang, A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, "The Resolved Distributions of Dust Mass and Temperature in Local Group Galaxies", 2019, ApJ, 874, 141.
- 1) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, L.C. Johnson, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, "The Spatially Resolved Dust-to-metals Ratio in M101", 2018, ApJ, 865, 117.

A full publication list at ADS Public Library is available here.

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS AS OTHER COAUTHOR

- 4) J. Chastenet, K. Sandstrom, **I-D. Chiang**, B.S. Hensley, B.T. Draine, K.D. Gordon, E.W. Koch, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, T.G. Williams, "Benchmarking Dust Emission Models in M101", 2020, $submitted\ to\ ApJ$.
- 3) J. Sun, A.K. Leroy, E.C. Ostriker, A. Hughes, E. Rosolowsky, A. Schruba, E. Schinnerer, G.A. Blanc, C. Faesi, J.M.D. Kruijssen, S. Meidt, D. Utomo, F. Bigiel, A.D. Bolatto, M. Chevance, I-D. Chiang, D. Dale, E. Emsellem, S.C.O. Glover, K. Grasha, J. Henshaw, C.N. Herrera, M.J. Jimenez-Donaire, J.C. Lee, J. Pety, M. Querejeta, T. Saito, K. Sandstrom, A. Usero, "Dynamical Equilibrium in the Molecular ISM in 28 Nearby Star-Forming Galaxies", 2020, ApJ, 892, 148.
- 2) A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, D. Lang, A. Lewis, E.A. Behrens, J. Chastenet, **I-D. Chiang**, M.J. Gallagher, D. Utomo, "A z=0 Multi-wavelength Galaxy Synthesis I: A WISE and GALEX Atlas of Local Galaxies", 2019, ApJS, 244, 24.
- 1) J. Chastenet, K.M. Sandstrom, **I-D. Chiang**, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, C. Bot, K.D. Gordon, B.T. Draine, Y. Fukui, T. Onishi, K. Tsuge, "Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon Fraction at ∼10 pc scale in the Magellanic Clouds", 2019, ApJ, 876, 62.

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Contributed talk, "Dust, gas and metals: Resolving the Dust Life Cycle in the Nearby Universe", The AAS 235th Meeting, Honolulu, USA 2020

Special seminar, "Dust-to-Metals Relation in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan

2019

Poster, ASROC2019, Taichung, Taiwan

2019

Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Contributed talk,"	2019
Lunch talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2019
Tea time talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2018
Poster, CPHDUST, Copenhagen, Denmark	2018
Poster, ASROC2018, Kinmen, Taiwan	2018
Lunch talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2018
EACHING EXPERIENCE	
Lab TA Coordinator, PHYS 1-ABC Lab – University of California, San Diego	2015 - 2016
Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – University of California, San Diego	2014 - 2015
Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – University of California, San Diego UTREACH EXPERIENCE	2014 - 2015
· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	,
UTREACH EXPERIENCE	2019
UTREACH EXPERIENCE Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter	2018 2018
UTREACH EXPERIENCE Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights – presenter	2014 - 2015 2019 2018 2017 2016
UTREACH EXPERIENCE Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights – presenter Tech Trek: University of California, San Diego – presenter	2018 2018 2017
Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights – presenter Tech Trek: University of California, San Diego – presenter Physics GRE bootcamp at UCSD – teaching assistant	2018 2018 2017 2016
Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights – presenter Tech Trek: University of California, San Diego – presenter Physics GRE bootcamp at UCSD – teaching assistant WARDS	2018 2018 2017